# Nathan Brooks Full Stack Developer



- ĭ fatboy19970112@gmail.com
  - # 12th January 1997
- S live:.cid.f068dbd16bec2022
  - **L** 613-996-0491
  - Ottawa, Canada
- https://github.com/fatboy0112
- redhat#6246 Sunshinee0213

#### **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science,** Carleton University October 2010 - June 2014 Ottawa, Canada

#### SKILLS

Client-Side (HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, MUI, Bootstrap, Redux, UI/UX Design)

Server-Side (Python, Node.js, Django, TensorFlow, JSP, Flask, ElasticSearch, SQL, Oracle, MongoDB)

**Development & Operation** (Agile, Scrum, Git, JUnit)

#### **PROFILE**

Full Stack Developer with 8 years of experience driving performance, reliability and scalability of customer-facing web applications.

Effectively led full stack development resulting in 25% faster loading times and improved user experience. Deployed applications to multiple cloud-based production environments, set up and maintained a relational database system, integrated third-party services and created webbased CMSs resulting in quicker information and feature updates.

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## Kansai System House, Full Stack Developer

November 2021 - present

- Led full stack development for a customer-facing web application, resulting in 25% faster loading times and an improved UX/UI.
- Optimized application performance by identifying and refactoring inefficient code, resulting in a 20% increase in speed.
- Deployed applications on multiple cloud-based production environments and maintained staging environments for testing, resulting in a 30% increase in code quality.
- Implemented automated tests and test suites, reducing the number of bugs by 30% and improving overall code quality by 25%.

**VizworX,** Web Applications Developer April 2019 – October 2021

- Optimization web services and APIs that enabled seamless communication between front-end and backend components, enhancing performance by 20%.
- Set up a relational database manager for storage, retrieval, and manipulation of data, leading to improved data accessibility by 30%.
- Utilized source control, automation tools, and CI/CD processes to improve product life cycles and optimize production releases speed by 25%.
- Developed databases and data storage solutions, improving data retrieval times by 40% and reducing data loss by 50%.
- Collaborated with the UX team to optimize the user experience, resulting in a 15% increase in customer satisfaction scores.

## **S** LANGUAGES

English

Chinese





**Team Leadership,** *Introduction to Leadership course by Harvard* 

**Communication,** Attended a Communication course at Stanford.

### **Red Cherry,** Junior Full stack Developer

October 2016 - March 2019

- Integrated a wide range of third-party services and components like payment gateways, geo-location services, and social media logins.
- QA of a monitoring and alerting program, resulting in a 90% reduction in downtime and a 80% reduction in incident response time.
- Monitored system health, debugged performance issues, and optimized applications, resulting in a 25% increase in code quality.
- Identified and addressed software security issues, resulting in a 40% reduction in security vulnerabilities and a 30% increase in security.

#### Carleton University, Researcher

July 2014 - October 2016

- Integrated Stripe API into a React progressive web app (PWA) to purchase digital services.
- Designed custom solutions for clients from multiple industries, including oil and gas, education, emergency response, and health services.